[{"Question":"1 Which task is undertaken by an accountant?","A":"extracting a trial balance","B":"maintaining a petty cash book","C":"preparing an income statement","D":"writing up a cash book","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"2 What are advantages of using ICT (Information and Communications Technology) in book-keeping and accounting? 1 Accounts are instantly updated and a new balance calculated after each entry. 2 Accuracy is increased as entries only need to be input once. 3 Documents such as invoices can be produced quickly and accurately.","A":"1 and 2 only","B":"1 only","C":"1, 2 and 3","D":"2 and 3 only","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"3 Which does not reduce the owner’s capital?","A":"business expenses paid using a personal cheque","B":"cash withdrawn from the business bank account for personal use","C":"goods taken from inventory for personal use","D":"personal expenses paid using business cash","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"4 A statement of account issued to a customer on 31 March 2019 showed the following information. invoices 250, credit note 10, cash discount 5% if payment made within 14 days of date of statement of account. The customer made payment on 12 April 2019. How much did the customer pay?","A":"$227.50","B":"$228","C":"$237.50","D":"$247","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"6 Suzi owed $200 for goods supplied by Mandy. Suzi paid the amount owing by cheque, after deducting a cash discount of $10. Which entries would Suzi make in Mandy’s account to record this transaction?","A":"credit entries: bank $190, discount $10","B":"credit entries: bank $200, discount $10","C":"debit entries: bank $190, discount $10","D":"debit entries: bank $200, discount $10","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"8 A trial balance is a listing of which balances?","A":"assets","B":"closing balances of all accounts","C":"liabilities","D":"opening balances of all accounts","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"9 A business purchased a motor vehicle, $8900, on credit from AKS Limited. The book-keeper made an error of reversal when recording this purchase. What was the incorrect debit entry he made?","A":"AKS Limited 8900","B":"AKS Limited 9800","C":"motor vehicles 8900","D":"motor vehicles 9800","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"10 Ali’s financial year ends on 31 March. During the year ended 31 March 2019, Ali paid wages of $42 500. On 31 March 2019, $1400 wages were accrued. Which journal entry records the transfer from the wages account to the income statement on 31 March 2019?","A":"income statement dr 42 500 wages cr 42 500","B":"income statement dr 43 900 wages 43 900","C":"wages dr 42 500 income statement cr 42 500","D":"wages income dr 43 900 statement cr 43 900","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"11 On 1 March 2019, a trader paid rent of $1200 covering the period 1 March 2019 to 31 May 2019. The trader’s financial year ends on 31 March 2019. What balance was brought down on the rent payable account on 1 April 2019?","A":"credit $400","B":"credit $800","C":"debit $400","D":"debit $800","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"12 An amount owed by Baloch was written off. Which entries were made?","A":"bad debts dr, Baloch cr","B":"bad debts dr, provision for doubtful debts cr","C":"Baloch dr, bad debts cr","D":"provision for doubtful debts dr, Baloch cr","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"13 Kevin depreciated his motor vehicle by $2000 at the end of the financial year. Which journal entry would record this?","A":"income statement dr 2000, provision for depreciation of motor vehicles cr 2000","B":"motor vehicles dr 2000, provision for depreciation of motor vehicles cr 2000","C":"provision for depreciation of motor vehicles dr 2000, income statement cr 2000","D":"provision for depreciation of motor vehicles dr 2000, motor vehicles cr 2000","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"14 Ravi’s financial year ends on 30 April. Ravi bought a motor vehicle for $8000 on 1 May 2016 and sold it for $4050 on 1 May 2018. He uses the diminishing (reducing) balance method of depreciation at 20% per annum. What would be recorded in the income statement for the year ended 30 April 2019 for the disposal of the motor vehicle?","A":"$750 loss","B":"$750 profit","C":"$1070 loss","D":"$1070 profit","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"15 Which would not appear in a sales ledger control account?","A":"bad debts written off","B":"cash discount allowed","C":"customer’s cheque dishonoured","D":"provision for doubtful debts","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"17 Which section of a statement of financial position would include goodwill?","A":"current assets","B":"current liabilities","C":"non-current assets","D":"non-current liabilities","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"18 At the end of the financial year Omar was owed $200 by a credit customer and he owed $10 for electricity. He also had a 2-year bank loan of $5000. In which sections of Omar’s statement of financial position will these items appear?  credit customer, unpaid electricity bill, loan from bank (answer according to order)","A":"current assets, current assets, non-current assets","B":"current assets, current liabilities, non-current liabilities","C":"current liabilities, non-current assets, current assets","D":"current liabilities, non-current liabilities, current liabilities","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"20 A golf club sells refreshments to its members. Suppliers of refreshments were owed $250 on 1 January 2018 and $400 on 31 December 2018. Payments to suppliers during the year were $7200. The inventory at the end of the year was $100 less than the inventory at the start of the year. What was the cost of sales of refreshments for the year ended 31 December 2018?","A":"$7050","B":"$7150","C":"$7300","D":"$7450","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"22 Sue started a business on 1 January 2019. The only accounting record she maintained was a bank account. Why is the balance on the bank account not equal to the profit for the year? 1 Expenses may be accrued at the year-end. 2 Goods may have been taken for personal use. 3 Non-current assets may have depreciated.","A":"1 and 2 only","B":"1 only","C":"1, 2 and 3","D":"2 and 3 only","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"24 What does not appear in a statement of changes in equity?","A":"debenture interest paid","B":"interim dividend paid on ordinary shares","C":"issue of ordinary shares","D":"transfer to general reserve","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"25 Which cost would be included in prime cost in a manufacturing account?","A":"depreciation of machinery","B":"factory manager’s salary","C":"insurance","D":"royalties","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"26 Jacob works 30 hours each week and is paid $10 per hour. He pays income tax at 30%, national insurance at 10% and makes a voluntary contribution to charity of 5%. What is his net weekly pay?","A":"$165","B":"$180","C":"$195","D":"$210","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"27 A business’s sales are $100 000, the expenses are $30 000 and the profit for the year is $20 000. What is the gross profit/sales ratio?","A":"10%","B":"50%","C":"70%","D":"80%","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"28 A trader provided the following information. profit for the year 24 000, working capital 20 000, capital 120 000, non-current liability 30 000. What was the return on capital employed?","A":"14.12%","B":"16.00%","C":"17.14%","D":"20.00%","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"29 A business prepares its accounts on the basis that it will continue to trade in the foreseeable future. Which accounting principle is being applied?","A":"accounting entity","B":"accounting year","C":"going concern","D":"matching/accruals","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"30 Which statement is not correct about reasons for using international accounting standards?","A":"helps when making comparisons between companies","B":"improves the reliability of accounting information","C":"narrows the areas of difference between companies","D":"makes the preparation of financial statements less time consuming","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is the main function of book-keeping?","A":"communicating information","B":"interpreting information","C":"recording information","D":"summarising information","Answer":"C","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which does not reduce the owner’s capital?","A":"business expenses paid using a personal cheque","B":"cash withdrawn from the business bank account for personal use","C":"goods taken from inventory for personal use","D":"personal expenses paid using business cash","Answer":"A","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What would be recorded by a debit entry in a ledger account?","A":"a decrease in an asset","B":"an increase in a liability","C":"an increase in an asset","D":"an increase in capital employed","Answer":"C","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"In April Meena sent Ralph invoices for $170, $240, $125 and a credit note for $63.  In the same month Ralph sent Meena a debit note for $70  and a cheque for $107. What was the balance on Meena’s account in Ralph’s books on 1 May?","A":"$295 credit","B":"$295 debit","C":"$365 credit","D":"$365 debit","Answer":"C","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"After receiving her bank statement Lyn updated her cash book. Which items would reduce the overdrawn balance in the cash book?, 1 bank interest received, 2 credit transfer received, 3 direct debit payment","A":"1 and 2 only","B":"1 and 3 only","C":"1, 2 and 3","D":"2 and 3 only","Answer":"A","Category":"Cashbook","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"After preparing a trial balance it was found that a cheque, $300, received from Oliver, had been debited in Oliver’s account and credited in the bank account. No other errors were found. Which statement about the trial balance before correcting the error is correct?","A":"The credit column was equal to the debit column.","B":"The credit column was $300 more than the debit column.","C":"The debit column was $300 more than the credit column.","D":"The debit column was $600 more than the credit column.","Answer":"A","Category":"Trial balance","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A trader created a provision for doubtful debts. Why did he create this provision? 1 to ensure that money was available to cover bad debts, 2 to ensure that the current assets were not overstated, 3 to ensure that the matching /accruals principle was followed, 4 to ensure that the profit for the year was not overstated","A":"1 and 3","B":"1 only","C":"2 and 4 only","D":"2, 3 and 4","Answer":"D","Category":"Bad debts","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which item is revenue expenditure for a manufacturer?","A":"buying new office equipment","B":"extending the factory","C":"purchasing motor vehicles","D":"repairing machinery","Answer":"D","Category":"Revenue and capital expenditure","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"An item of revenue expenditure was treated as an item of capital expenditure. What was the effect of this error? Answer in the format: profit for the year, non-current assets","A":"overstated, overstated","B":"overstated, understated","C":"understated, overstated","D":"understated, understated","Answer":"A","Category":"Journal entries and correction of errors","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What causes computer equipment to depreciate?","A":"depletion","B":"economic reasons","C":"passage of time","D":"physical deterioration","Answer":"B","Category":"Depreciation","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which items are used to calculate cost of goods sold?","A":"carriage on purchases, carriage on sales, net purchases, opening inventory","B":"carriage on purchases, closing inventory, net purchases, opening inventory","C":"carriage on sales, closing inventory, net purchases, opening inventory","D":"carriage on sales, closing inventory, net purchases, sales returns","Answer":"B","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is an advantage of trading as a partnership?","A":"A partnership is a separate legal entity.","B":"Decision-making is easy and quick.","C":"Liability is unlimited.","D":"Responsibilities are shared.","Answer":"D","Category":"Partnerships","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A golf club sells refreshments to its members. Suppliers of refreshments were owed $250 on 1 January 2018 and $400 on 31 December 2018. Payments to suppliers during the year were $7200. The inventory at the end of the year was $100 less than the inventory at the start of the year. What was the cost of sales of refreshments for the year ended 31 December 2018?","A":"$7050","B":"$7150","C":"$7300","D":"$7450","Answer":"D","Category":"Other payables and other receivables","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A business provided the following information. Sales 100 000, opening inventory 40 000, closing inventory 30 000, gross profit 5 000, What was the value of the purchases?","A":"$85 000","B":"$95 000","C":"$105 000","D":"$115 000","Answer":"A","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is not included in a statement of changes in equity of a limited company for the year ended 31 March 2019?","A":"an issue of additional ordinary shares that was made during the year","B":"an interim dividend paid to the ordinary shareholders on 1 November 2018","C":"a proposed final dividend which is to be paid to ordinary shareholders on 1 August 2019","D":"a transfer made to general reserve from retained earnings on 31 March 2019","Answer":"C","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A business’s sales are $100 000, the expenses are $30 000 and the profit for the year is $20 000. What is the gross profit/sales ratio?","A":"10%","B":"50%","C":"70%","D":"80%","Answer":"B","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A business prepares its accounts on the basis that it will continue to trade in the foreseeable future. Which accounting principle is being applied?","A":"accounting entity","B":"accounting year","C":"going concern","D":"matching/accruals","Answer":"C","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A cheque paid by a business for fuel for the delivery vehicle was recorded in the books of the business. A cheque paid by the business owner for fuel for his motorcycle was not recorded in the books of the business. Which accounting principle was applied?","A":"accounting entity","B":"going concern","C":"materiality","D":"money measurement","Answer":"A","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which statement is not correct about reasons for using international accounting standards?","A":"helps when making comparisons between companies","B":"improves the reliability of accounting information","C":"narrows the areas of difference between companies","D":"makes the preparation of financial statements less time consuming","Answer":"D","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2019(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which statements about book-keeping and accounting are correct? Accounting is performed periodically rather than daily. Accounting relies on having accurate book-keeping records. Book-keeping includes the preparation of financial statements. Book-keeping involves the recording of financial transac","A":"1, 2 and 4","B":"1 and 3","C":"2, 3 and 4","D":"2 and 4","Answer":"A","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A trader invested $4000 into the business. $2000 was used to pay a credit supplier. The rest of the money was paid into the business bank account. What changes would take place within the accounting equation?","A":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities –$2000 –$4000 +$2000","B":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities +$2000 +$2000 no effect","C":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities +$2000 +$4000 –$2000","D":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities +$4000 +$4000 no effect","Answer":"C","Category":"Journal entries and correction of errors","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Wilma bought 55 items from Margot at a list price of $40 each, subject to a 15% trade discount. Wilma later returned 25 items as they were faulty. Which document did Margot issue to Wilma for the returned items?","A":"credit note for $850","B":"credit note for $1000","C":"debit note for $850","D":"debit note for $1000","Answer":"A","Category":"Business documents","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"The bank agreed to allow Dan an overdraft with a limit of $500. What did this mean?","A":"A sum of $500 would be transferred into Dan’s account by the bank.","B":"All cheques issued by Dan would be paid by the bank.","C":"Cheques issued by Dan would be paid by the bank provided the account was not overdrawn by more than $500.","D":"Only cheques issued by Dan for less than $500 would be paid by the bank if there was not enough money in the account.","Answer":"C","Category":"Bank reconciliation statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"On 30 September 2018, Ahmed’s bank statement showed a credit balance of $2500. Ahmed found that a cheque issued for $90 and a deposit of $500 had not been included on the bank statement. What was the balance at bank shown in Ahmed’s cash book on 30 September 2018?","A":"$1910","B":"$2090","C":"$2910","D":"$3090","Answer":"C","Category":"Bank reconciliation statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which statement about a debit balance brought down on a ledger account is not correct?","A":"It may represent a loss.","B":"It may represent a prepaid expense","C":"It may represent an accrued expense.","D":"It may represent an asset.","Answer":"C","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"On 1 September 2018 Chan owed Tan $570. During September 2018 the following transactions took place. Tan sold goods, $380, on credit to Chan Chan returned goods, $150, to Tan Chan paid Tan $500 by cheque What was the balance brought down on Chan’s account in Tan’s ledger on 1 October 2018?","A":"$300 credit","B":"$300 debit","C":"$840 credit","D":"$840 debit","Answer":"B","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which name is given to a statement of ledger balances on a particular date?","A":"bank reconciliation statement","B":"general ledger","C":"statement of financial position","D":"trial balance","Answer":"D","Category":"Trial balance","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"The balance of which account will appear in the debit column of a trial balance?","A":"carriage inwards","B":"discounts received","C":"provision for doubtful debts","D":"purchases returns","Answer":"A","Category":"Trial balance","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Ella rents business premises. She owed rent at both the start and the end of the financial year. How can rent payable for the year be calculated?","A":"rent paid – amount owing at start of year","B":"rent paid – amount owing at start of year + amount owing at end of year","C":"rent paid + amount owing at end of year","D":"rent paid + amount owing at start of year – amount owing at end of year","Answer":"B","Category":"Other payables and other receivables","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Bashir maintains a provision for doubtful debts of 3% of the trade receivables at the end of the year. On 31 August 2017 trade receivables amounted to $70 000. On 31 August 2018 trade receivables amounted to $73 000. Which double entry should Bashir make on 31 August 2018?","A":"debit $ credit $ income statement 90 provision for doubtful debts account 90","B":"debit $ credit $ income statement 2100 provision for doubtful debts account 2100","C":"debit $ credit $ provision for doubtful debts account 90 income statement 90","D":"debit $ credit $ provision for doubtful debts account 2100 income statement 2100","Answer":"A","Category":"Bad debts","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Leroy has an engineering business. On 31 May he received an invoice from AB Machines showing the following: cost of replacement parts for machine cost of repairs to machine cost of machine cost of installation of machine Which costs are capital expenditure in Leroy’s books?","A":"machine, installation","B":"machine only","C":"replacement parts, machine","D":"replacement parts, repairs, installation","Answer":"A","Category":"Revenue and capital expenditure","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Why is depreciation charged on a non-current asset?","A":"to accumulate a fund of money to replace the asset","B":"to charge the cost of using the asset against income","C":"to determine the market value of the asset","D":"to ensure that profits are not understated","Answer":"B","Category":"Depreciation","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Chris purchased a machine costing $15 000 on 1 January 2016. He depreciates the machine using the diminishing (reducing) balance method at 20% per annum. Which journal entry did Chris make on 31 December 2017?","A":"debit $ credit $ income statement 2400 provision for depreciation of machinery 2400","B":"debit $ credit $ income statement 3000 provision for depreciation of machinery 3000","C":"debit $ credit $ provision for depreciation of machinery 2400 income statement 2400","D":"debit $ credit $ provision for depreciation of machinery 3000 income statement 3000","Answer":"A","Category":"Depreciation","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Hossam took out a 5-year bank loan on 1 January 2018. All of the money borrowed was used to purchase a delivery van. Under which heading will these items be shown in Hossam’s statement of financial position on  31 March 2018?","A":"bank loan delivery van current liability current asset","B":"bank loan delivery van current liability non-current asset","C":"bank loan delivery van non-current liability current asset","D":"bank loan delivery van non-current liability non-current asset","Answer":"D","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Beth provided the following information at 31 December 2017. capital 1 January 2017\t26 000 profit for the year\t3 600 drawings\t2 500 long-term loan\t8 000 Beth paid a personal cheque to the business on 30 December 2017 amounting to $5000. What was the capital employed on 31 December 2017?","A":"$24 100","B":"$32 100","C":"$35 100","D":"$40 100","Answer":"D","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which businesses do not prepare a trading account section of an income statement? furniture store, gym, newsagent, toy shop, window-cleaner.","A":"1 and 2","B":"2 and 5","C":"3 and 4","D":"3 and 5","Answer":"B","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"X and Y are sole traders. They decided to form a partnership. Which group contains only disadvantages of forming a partnership?","A":"disagreements may occur between the partners, profits are shared","B":"disagreements may occur between the partners, risks are shared","C":"losses are shared, responsibilities are shared","D":"profits are shared, risks are shared","Answer":"A","Category":"Partnerships","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which may be included in an income and expenditure account?","A":"bad debts","B":"opening balance on the bank account","C":"purchase of equipment","D":"subscriptions received for the following financial year","Answer":"A","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"At the end of the financial year a sports club owed rent for the clubhouse. Some members had paid their subscriptions in advance for the following year. How would these items be recorded in the club’s statement of financial position?","A":"rent owing subscriptions paid in advance current asset current asset","B":"rent owing subscriptions paid in advance current asset current liability","C":"rent owing subscriptions paid in advance current liability current asset","D":"rent owing subscriptions paid in advance current liability current liability","Answer":"D","Category":"Clubs and societies","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A business provided the following information. opening inventory\t$8000, closing inventory\t$10 000, rate of turnover of inventory\t12 times, mark-up\t50%, What was the revenue?","A":"$54 000","B":"$108 000","C":"$162 000","D":"$180 000","Answer":"C","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which group contains only indirect costs?","A":"carriage inwards, factory rent, wages of factory supervisors","B":"carriage inwards, raw materials, wages of machine operators","C":"depreciation of machinery, factory rent, wages of factory supervisors","D":"depreciation of machinery, raw materials, wages of machine operators","Answer":"C","Category":"Revenue and capital expenditure","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A manufacturing business provided the following information. prime cost\t250 000, factory overhead expenses\t50 000, office and selling expenses\t25 000, work-in-progress at 1 January\t1 500, work-in-progress at 31 December\t2 500, What was the production cost of goods completed?","A":"$249 000","B":"$299 000","C":"$301 000","D":"$324 000","Answer":"B","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which items are statutory deductions from an employee’s gross pay?","A":"donation to charity and club subscription","B":"donation to charity and social security contribution","C":"income tax and club subscription","D":"income tax and social security contribution","Answer":"D","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Karim works 40 hours a week at a rate of $5 per hour and any overtime is paid at time and a half. He is paid monthly in arrears. He worked 12 hours, 16 hours and 18 hours overtime in May, June and July respectively. How much was Karim paid in June? (Assume 4 weeks in a month)","A":"$800","B":"$890","C":"$920","D":"$935","Answer":"B","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is included in the working capital ratio (current ratio), but not the quick ratio (acid test  ratio)?","A":"cash","B":"inventory","C":"other receivables","D":"trade payables","Answer":"B","Category":"Ratio Analysis and interpretation","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Kim has been in business for many years and expects this will continue. She provided the following information. premises\t at cost\t50 000, at market value\t65 000, trade receivables\t at book value\t14 000, Trade receivables included a debt of $2000 which was unlikely to be paid. At which total value were these assets recorded in Kim’s statement of financial position?","A":"$62 000","B":"$64 000","C":"$77 000","D":"$79 000","Answer":"A","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of international accounting standards?","A":"to allow users to rely on the information in financial statements being error-free","B":"to enable accountants to get work easily anywhere in the world","C":"to enable non-accountants to understand all the information in financial statements","D":"to make it easier to compare financial statements prepared in different countries","Answer":"D","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Ava had $4000 in the bank. She paid a supplier $575 by cheque in full settlement of $600 owing. Which changes would take place within the accounting equation?","A":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities –$600 –$25 –$625","B":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities –$600 +$25 –$625","C":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities –$575 +$25 –$600","D":"assets owner’s equity (capital) liabilities +$575 –$25 +$600","Answer":"C","Category":"Other payables and other receivables","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Winston returned goods to Hanif. Which entries will Winston make in his ledgers?","A":"debit entry credit entry ledger account ledger account general Hanif purchases purchases returns","B":"debit entry credit entry ledger account ledger account general purchases returns purchases Hanif","C":"debit entry credit entry ledger account ledger account purchases Hanif general purchases returns","D":"debit entry credit entry ledger account ledger account purchases purchases returns general Hanif","Answer":"C","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"On 30 September 2018, Ahmed’s bank statement showed a credit balance of $2500. Ahmed found that a cheque issued for $90 and a deposit of $500 had not been included on the bank statement. What was the balance at bank shown in Ahmed’s cash book on 30 September 2018?","A":"$1910","B":"$2090","C":"$2910","D":"$3090","Answer":"C","Category":"Bank reconciliation statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"On 1 September 2018 Chan owed Tan $570. During September 2018 the following transactions took place. Tan sold goods, $380, on credit to Chan Chan returned goods, $150, to Tan Chan paid Tan $500 by cheque What was the balance brought down on Chan’s account in Tan’s ledger on 1 October 2018?","A":"$300 credit","B":"$300 debit","C":"$840 credit","D":"$840 debit","Answer":"B","Category":"Double entry book-keeping","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Seema’s financial year ends on 30 September. She rents premises at a monthly rent of $2000. During the year ended 30 September 2018 she paid $26 000 rent. Which journal entry will Seema make on 30 September 2018 to transfer the rent to the income statement?","A":"debit $ credit $ income statement 24 000 rent 24000","B":"debit $ credit $ income statement 26 000 rent 26 000","C":"debit $ credit $ rent 24 000 income statement 24 000","D":"debit $ credit $ rent 26 000 income statement 26 000","Answer":"A","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Bashir maintains a provision for doubtful debts of 3% of the trade receivables at the end of the year. On 31 August 2017 trade receivables amounted to $70 000. On 31 August 2018 trade receivables amounted to $73 000. Which double entry should Bashir make on 31 August 2018?","A":"debit $ credit $ income statement 90 provision for doubtful debts account 90","B":"debit $ credit $ income statement 2100 provision for doubtful debts account 2100","C":"debit $ credit $ provision for doubtful debts account 90 income statement 90","D":"debit $ credit $ provision for doubtful debts account 2100 income statement 2100","Answer":"A","Category":"Bad debts","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Leroy has an engineering business. On 31 May he received an invoice from AB Machines showing the following: cost of replacement parts for machine cost of repairs to machine cost of machine cost of installation of machine Which costs are capital expenditure in Leroy’s books?","A":"machine, installation","B":"machine only","C":"replacement parts, machine","D":"replacement parts, repairs, installation","Answer":"A","Category":"Revenue and capital expenditure","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Why is depreciation charged on a non-current asset?","A":"to accumulate a fund of money to replace the asset","B":"to charge the cost of using the asset against income","C":"to determine the market value of the asset","D":"to ensure that profits are not understated","Answer":"B","Category":"Depreciation","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Sally bought a non-current asset. It was to be used for 10 years, after which it would have no scrap value. Sally used the straight-line method of depreciation. Which statements are correct?","A":"accumulated depreciation after five years annual depreciation charge equalled half of cost decreased each year","B":"accumulated depreciation after five years annual depreciation charge equalled half of cost was constant","C":"accumulated depreciation after five years annual depreciation charge was more than half of cost decreased each year","D":"accumulated depreciation after five years annual depreciation charge was more than half of cost was constant","Answer":"B","Category":"Depreciation","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A draft income statement showed a gross profit of $12 200. It was later found that carriage on purchases, $260, and carriage on sales, $230, had both been included as expenses in the profit and loss section of the income statement. What was the corrected gross profit?","A":"$11 710","B":"$11 940","C":"$12 460","D":"$12 690","Answer":"B","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Raj is both a customer of and a supplier to Balbir. Raj’s account in Balbir’s sales ledger showed a debit balance of $300. There was a credit balance of $100 on Raj’s account in the purchases ledger. A contra entry between the two accounts was agreed. Which entry would Balbir make in Raj’s account in the purchases ledger?","A":"credit $100","B":"credit $200","C":"debit $100","D":"debit $200","Answer":"C","Category":"Control accounts","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Michael’s financial year ends on 31 August. On 30 August 2018 he purchased a motor  vehicle using a bank loan which is repayable on       30 August 2020. On 31 August 2018 Michael had a bank overdraft. In which sections of Michael’s statement of financial position on 31 August 2018 did these items appear?","A":"motor vehicle bank loan bank overdraft current asset current liability non-current liability","B":"motor vehicle bank loan bank overdraft current asset non-current liability current liability","C":"motor vehicle bank loan bank overdraft non-current asset current liability non-current liability","D":"motor vehicle bank loan bank overdraft non-current asset non-current liability current liability","Answer":"D","Category":"Financial statements","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which may be included in an income and expenditure account?","A":"bad debts","B":"opening balance on the bank account","C":"purchase of equipment","D":"subscriptions received for the following financial year","Answer":"A","Category":"Clubs and societies","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A club’s financial year ends on 31 July. During the year ended 31 July 2018 the following subscriptions were received. subscriptions for the year ended 31 July 2017 50, subscriptions for the year ended 31 July 2018 3400, subscriptions for the year ending 31 July 2019 20, How much would  be  included  in  the  receipts  and  payments  account  for  the  year  ended  31 July 2018?","A":"$3400","B":"$3420","C":"$3450","D":"$3470","Answer":"D","Category":"Clubs and societies","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A trader does not keep full accounting records. How can credit purchases for his first year of trading be calculated?","A":"cheques paid + discounts received + amount owing to suppliers at year end","B":"cheques paid + discounts received – amount owing to suppliers at year end","C":"cheques paid – discounts received + amount owing to suppliers at year end","D":"cheques paid – discounts received – amount owing to suppliers at year end","Answer":"A","Category":"Journal entries and correction of errors","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A trader provided the following information. revenue\t100 000, cost of sales\t60 000, gross profit\t40 000, profit for the year\t20 000. What was the mark-up?","A":"20%","B":"33.33%","C":"40%","D":"66.67%","Answer":"D","Category":"Ratio Analysis and interpretation","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which statements about ordinary shares are correct? 1 If a company is wound up ordinary shares are repaid after debentures, 2 Ordinary shares are a non-current liability of the company, 3 The holders of ordinary shares are the owners of the company.","A":"1 and 3","B":"1 only","C":"2 and 3","D":"3 only","Answer":"A","Category":"Shares and capital","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which items are included in the equity section of the statement of financial position of a limited company?","A":"ordinary shares, retained earnings, debentures and current liabilities","B":"ordinary shares, retained earnings and debentures only","C":"ordinary shares and retained earnings only","D":"ordinary shares only","Answer":"C","Category":"Shares and capital","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"During the financial year, a manufacturing company’s payments included the following. purchase of a new machine running costs of the machine Where would these appear in the financial statements prepared at the end of the financial year?","A":"machine running costs of machine manufacturing account income statement","B":"machine running costs of machine manufacturing account manufacturing account","C":"machine running costs of machine statement of financial position income statement","D":"machine running costs of machine statement of financial position manufacturing account","Answer":"D","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which group contains only indirect costs?","A":"carriage inwards, factory rent, wages of factory supervisors","B":"carriage inwards, raw materials, wages of machine operators","C":"depreciation of machinery, factory rent, wages of factory supervisors","D":"depreciation of machinery, raw materials, wages of machine operators","Answer":"C","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A factory employee records his time of arrival and departure each day. Which document is used for recording his hours of work?","A":"clock card","B":"payroll register","C":"time sheet","D":"wages sheet","Answer":"A","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which items are statutory deductions from an employee’s gross pay?","A":"donation to charity and club subscription","B":"donation to charity and social security contribution","C":"income tax and club subscription","D":"income tax and social security contribution","Answer":"D","Category":"Manufacturing accounts","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A trader provided the following information. revenue\t95 000, purchases\t40 000, opening inventory\t20 000, closing inventory\t18 000, cost of sales\t42 000, What was the rate of turnover of inventory?","A":"2.10 times","B":"2.21 times","C":"5 times","D":"5.28 times","Answer":"B","Category":"Ratio Analysis and interpretation","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A business provided the following information about its percentage of gross profit to sales. Year 1\t40%,  Year 2\t38%, Year 3\t35%, What could explain the changes in the percentage of gross profit to sales?","A":"Cost of sales is decreasing.","B":"Expenses are decreasing.","C":"Quantity of goods sold is decreasing.","D":"Selling price is decreasing.","Answer":"D","Category":"Ratio Analysis and interpretation","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A business values its inventory at the lower of cost and net realisable value. Which accounting principle is being applied?","A":"accounting entity","B":"dual aspect","C":"money measurement","D":"prudence","Answer":"D","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of international accounting standards?","A":"to allow users to rely on the information in financial statements being error-free","B":"to enable accountants to get work easily anywhere in the world","C":"to enable non-accountants to understand all the information in financial statements","D":"to make it easier to compare financial statements prepared in different countries","Answer":"D","Category":"Principles of accounting","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which statement about a computerised accounting system is correct?","A":"The general ledger does not include non-current asset accounts.","B":"The income statement always shows a profit.","C":"The statement of financial position does not include non-current assets.","D":"The trial balance always balances.","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which group contains only liabilities?","A":"bank loan, trade payables, prepaid rent","B":"bank overdraft, trade payables, unpaid wages","C":"trade payables, cash at bank, unpaid rates","D":"trade payables, inventory, unpaid wages","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is the accounting equation?","A":"assets – liabilities = capital","B":"assets + liabilities = capital","C":"liabilities – assets = capital","D":"liabilities – capital = assets","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Omar returned faulty goods to Yasmin, the supplier. Which document did Omar send to Yasmin?","A":"credit note","B":"debit note","C":"invoic","D":"statement of account","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What may a credit balance on a ledger account represent?","A":"accrued income","B":"asset","C":"expense","D":"prepaid income","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"The totals of a trial balance did not agree. The total of the debit column was $13 400. It was found that the purchases journal had been overcast by $195 and goods bought from supplier X for $85 had been incorrectly credited to Y. What was the total of the credit column of the trial balance?","A":"$13 120","B":"$13 205","C":"$13 595","D":"$13 680","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Leo is unable to pay the debt he owes to Sam. Which entry did Sam make to write off this bad debt?","A":"debit credit bad debts account income statement","B":"debit credit bad debts account Leo account","C":"debit credit income statement Leo account","D":"debit credit Leo account income statement","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Rashid maintains a provision for doubtful debts of 5% of the trade receivables at the end of each year. Trade receivables owed $40 000 on 31 March 2017. Trade receivables owed $46 000 on 31 March 2018. Which journal entry should Rashid make on 31 March 2018?","A":"debit $ credit $ income statement 300 provision for doubtful debts 300","B":"debit $ credit $ income statement 2300 provision for doubtful debts 2300","C":"debit $ credit $ provision for doubtful debts 300 income statement 300","D":"debit $ credit $ provision for doubtful debts 2300 income statement 2300","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What are examples of revenue receipts? 1)a cheque received from the sale of a non-current asset at book value, 2)a profit made on the sale of a non-current asset, 3)a loan from a bank that is repayable in 2020, 4)discounts received from credit suppliers for prompt payment","A":"1 and 3","B":"1 and 4","C":"2 and 3","D":"2 and 4","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Jon paid $18 000 for machinery on 1 January 2016. He depreciated this asset using the diminishing (reducing) balance method at 5% per annum. What was the balance on the provision for depreciation account on 1 January 2018?","A":"$1755 credit","B":"$1755 debit","C":"$1800 credit","D":"$1800 debit","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A motor vehicle cost $20 000. It was sold for $12 000. At the date of disposal the motor vehicle had been depreciated by $7200. Which journal entry records the closing of the disposal account?","A":"debit $ credit $ disposal account 800 income statement 800","B":"debit $ credit $ disposal account 8000 income statement 8000","C":"debit $ credit $ income statement 800 disposal account 800","D":"debit $ credit $ income statement 800 disposal account 800","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"James was late paying an invoice issued by Henry. Henry charged James interest on the overdue amount. Which entry would be made in Henry’s control accounts?","A":"credit purchases ledger control account","B":"credit sales ledger control account","C":"debit purchases ledger control account","D":"debit sales ledger control account","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Dennis runs a business with two departments, one selling carpets and one selling furniture. Total sales were $210 000 of which 60% related to the carpet department. The total gross profit was $54 600 of which 60% related to the furniture department. What was the cost of sales of the carpet department?","A":"$51 240","B":"$62 160","C":"$93 240","D":"$104 160","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which is an intangible asset?","A":"buildings","B":"goodwill","C":"inventory","D":"trade receivables","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A business has no non-current liabilities. What is added to the non-current assets in order to calculate the capital employed?","A":"current assets","B":"current liabilities","C":"owner’s capital","D":"working capital","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which item is credited in a partnership appropriation account?","A":"interest on capital","B":"interest on drawings","C":"partners’ drawings","D":"partners’ salaries","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Y and Z formed a partnership and agreed to share profits equally. Y deposited $30 000 into the business bank account. Z introduced a motor vehicle worth $15 000 and goodwill of $15 000. How should these transactions be recorded in the books of the partnership?","A":"accounts to be debited $ accounts to be credited $ bank 30 000 capital Y 30 000 goodwill 15 000 capital Z 30 000 motor vehicle 15 000","B":"accounts to be debited $ accounts to be credited $ bank 30 000 capital Y 37 500 goodwill 15 000 capital Z 22 500 motor vehicle 15 000","C":"accounts to be debited $ accounts to be credited $ Capital Y 30 000 Bank 30 0000 capital Z 30 000 goodwill 15 000 motor vehicle 15 000","D":"accounts to be debited $ accounts to be credited $ Capital Y 37 500 Bank 30 0000 capital Z 22 500 goodwill 15 000 motor vehicle 15 000","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A business provided the following information. revenue \t100 000 gross profit 20 000 What was the percentage mark-up?","A":"20%","B":"25%","C":"75%","D":"80%","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A trader does not keep a full set of accounting records. How can he calculate credit sales?","A":"cheques received from customers + owed by customers at start of year + owed by customers at end of year","B":"cheques received from customers + owed by customers at start of year – owed by customers at end of year","C":"cheques received from customers – owed by customers at start of year + owed by customers at end of year","D":"cheques received from customers – owed by customers at start of year – owed by customers at end of year","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which item would be entered in a statement of changes in equity?","A":"debenture interest accrued","B":"debenture interest paid","C":"ordinary dividend paid for current year","D":"ordinary dividend proposed for current year","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"On 1 January NH Limited was formed with the issue of 200 000 ordinary shares of $0.50 each. During the first year it made a profit of $21 000. A dividend of $0.02 per share was paid and $10 000 was transferred to general reserve. What was the total of reserves on 31 December?","A":"$7000","B":"$9000","C":"$17 000","D":"$19 000","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which type of labour would be classified as direct? factory managers, factory office staff, factory production workers.","A":"1, 2 and 3","B":"1 and 3 only","C":"2 only","D":"3 only","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A manufacturing business provided the following information. prime cost\t30 500,  factory overheads\t17 200, cost of goods produced\t46 000,  office and selling expenses\t9 500,  opening work-in-progress\t5 100,  What was the value of the closing work-in-progress?","A":"$1700","B":"$3400","C":"$6800","D":"$16 300","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which document is used to inform employees of their social security / national insurance contributions?","A":"clock card","B":"payroll register","C":"payslip","D":"time sheet","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A trader spreads the cost of a machine over the years which benefit from the use of that machine. Which accounting principle is being applied?","A":"accounting year","B":"dual aspect","C":"matching / accruals","D":"materiality","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which statement about a computerised accounting system is correct?","A":"The general ledger does not include non-current asset accounts.","B":"The income statement always shows a profit.","C":"The statement of financial position does not include non-current assets.","D":"The trial balance always balances.","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which item is a liability?","A":"accrued interest on loan to employee","B":"insurance premium paid in advance","C":"rent receivable paid in advance","D":"short-term loan to employee","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is the accounting equation?","A":"assets – liabilities = capital","B":"assets + liabilities = capital","C":"liabilities – assets = capital","D":"liabilities – capital = assets","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A retailer received a credit note from his wholesaler. Where would the wholesaler record this?","A":"cash book","B":"general journal","C":"purchases returns journal","D":"sales returns journal","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"The balance of the bank column in a trader’s cash book was $520 debit. The trader discovered the following did not appear on the bank statement. A cheque, $80, paid to a supplier. A cheque, $470, paid into the bank. What was the balance on the trader’s bank statement?","A":"$130 credit","B":"$130 debit","C":"$910 credit","D":"$910 debit","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which error is an error of principle?","A":"A cheque for $100 received from X was credited to Y’s account.","B":"A purchase invoice of $400 had not been entered in the ledger accounts.","C":"A purchase of a delivery vehicle, $12 000, was debited to the purchases account.","D":"Rent paid, $200, was debited to the bank account and credited to the rent account.","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which type of error is corrected using a suspense account?","A":"commission","B":"compensating","C":"original entry","D":"single entry","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"James was late paying an invoice issued by Henry. Henry charged James interest on the overdue amount. Which entry would be made in Henry’s control accounts?","A":"credit purchases ledger control account","B":"credit sales ledger control account","C":"debit purchases ledger control account","D":"debit sales ledger control account","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which is an intangible asset?","A":"buildings","B":"goodwill","C":"inventory","D":"trade receivables","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A business has no non-current liabilities. What is added to the non-current assets in order to calculate the capital employed?","A":"current assets","B":"current liabilities","C":"owner’s capital","D":"working capital","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which is a service business?","A":"a bakery","B":"a car showroom","C":"a hairdresser","D":"a newsagent","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"At the end of Carol’s financial year on 30 April 2018, a tenant had paid rent in advance. What was the effect of adjusting for this prepaid rent?","A":"increase profit for the year, increase current assets","B":"increase profit for the year, increase current liabilities","C":"reduce profit for the year, increase current assets","D":"reduce profit for the year, increase current liabilities","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What would not appear in the receipts and payments account of a sports club?","A":"cost of repairing equipment","B":"depreciation of equipment","C":"proceeds of sale of old equipment","D":"purchase of new equipment","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which item would be entered in a statement of changes in equity?","A":"debenture interest accrued","B":"debenture interest paid","C":"ordinary dividend paid for current year","D":"ordinary dividend proposed for current year","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"On 1 January NH Limited was formed with the issue of 200 000 ordinary shares of $0.50 each. During the first year it made a profit of $21 000. A dividend of $0.02 per share was paid and $10 000 was transferred to general reserve. What was the total of reserves on 31 December?","A":"$7000","B":"$9000","C":"$17 000","D":"$19 000","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is included in prime cost in a manufacturing account?","A":"carriage outwards","B":"depreciation of factory machinery","C":"factory manager’s salary","D":"royalties","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Where is work-in-progress shown in the statement of financial position of a manufacturing business?","A":"current assets","B":"current liabilities","C":"non-current assets","D":"non-current liabilities","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A company provided the following information about its working capital ratio (current ratio). Year 1 2 : 1, Year 2 1.8 : 1, Year 3 1.6 : 1. What would explain the changes in the ratio?","A":"Cash at bank is increasing.","B":"Inventory is increasing.","C":"Trade payables are increasing.","D":"Trade receivables are increasing.","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What will not be included in the accounting records of a business?","A":"cash received from sales","B":"cost of goods sold","C":"quality of product produced","D":"value of inventory held","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"MAY2018(13)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which statement about a computerised accounting system is correct?","A":"Anyone with a computer can gain access to the accounting records.","B":"Data input can only be used for one specific purpose.","C":"Data output can only be understood by computer programmers.","D":"Operator error may result in inaccurate information.","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What increases owner’s capital?","A":"bank loan extended from five to ten years","B":"purchase of inventory on credit","C":"purchase of machinery by cheque","D":"transfer of vehicle to business from private use","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which transaction is recorded in the general journal?","A":"payment of cash into a business bank account","B":"purchase of a motor vehicle on credit","C":"receipt of a cheque from a customer","D":"sale of goods on credit","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"The totals of a trial balance agreed. What does this mean?","A":"All the arithmetic in the ledger is correct.","B":"All transactions have been entered in the correct ledger accounts.","C":"All transactions have been entered on the correct sides of the ledger.","D":"Total debit balances equal total credit balances in the ledger.","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which are examples of capital receipts? 1 a loan received from a bank, repayable in three years’ time. 2 a profit made on the sale of a non-current asset. 3 cash received from the sale of a non-current asset at book value. 4 rent received from letting part of the business premises to a tenant.","A":"1 and 3","B":"1 and 4","C":"2 and 3","D":"2 and 4","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A café owner decided to use the revaluation method to calculate depreciation on the kitchen equipment. Kitchen equipment costing $3200 was purchased on 1 January 2016. This was expected to have a useful life of 4 years. Additional kitchen equipment was purchased during the year for $400. The total kitchen equipment was valued at $2900 on 31 December 2016. What was the depreciation charge for the year ended 31 December 2016?","A":"$300","B":"$700","C":"$800","D":"$900","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Imran’s financial year ends on 31 December. A machine purchased on 1 January 2015 for $20 000 was sold on 30 June 2017 for $8500. The machine had been depreciated using the straight-line method at 25% per annum on a month by month basis. What was the profit or loss on the disposal of the machine?","A":"loss $1000","B":"loss $1500","C":"profit $1000","D":"profit $1500","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Anita’s business has two departments, X and Y. She provided the following information for department X. expenses 28 000, profit for the year 9 000 Total revenue for the year was $180000 of which one-third related to department X. What was the gross profit of department X?","A":"$19 000","B":"$32 000","C":"$37 000","D":"$51 000","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"How is owner’s equity calculated?","A":"non-current assets + current assets – current liabilities – non-current liabilities","B":"non-current assets + current assets + current liabilities + non-current liabilities","C":"non-current assets – current assets – current liabilities – non-current liabilities","D":"non-current assets – current assets + current liabilities + non-current liabilities","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"David provided the following information. capital employed 435 000, non-current assets 200 000, current liabilities 124 000. What was the total of his current assets?","A":"$235 000","B":"$359 000","C":"$559 000","D":"$759 000","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Gurpreet is a broker and receives a commission from an insurance company when a client purchases a car insurance policy. The following information is available for the year ended 31 March 2017. commission received from insurance company 15 000, commission on policies arranged in  March 2017 not yet received 1 200, office rent 2 500, depreciation of non-current assets 900, heating and lighting 520. What was the profit for the year?","A":"$10 780","B":"$11 080","C":"$11 980","D":"$12 280","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is the disadvantage to a sole trader of bringing in a partner?","A":"The business will benefit from the knowledge of the new partner.","B":"The new partner may bring additional capital into the business.","C":"The profits made by the business will have to be shared with the new partner.","D":"The responsibility for running the business may be shared with the new partner.","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A club had an accumulated fund at the start of the year of $18 000 and at the end of the year of $16 200. Total running costs for the year were $9550. New equipment costing $1100 was bought during the year. The only income came from subscriptions. How much were subscriptions for the year?","A":"$7750","B":"$8850","C":"$11 350","D":"$12 450","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Karim did not keep proper accounting records, but was able to provide the following information. capital at 1 January 58 000, drawings during the year 8 500, capital introduced in the year 15 000, capital at 31 December 82 500, What was the profit for the year?","A":"$16 000","B":"$18 000","C":"$33 000","D":"$48 000","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A trader has not kept proper accounting records for his business. What will he use when calculating trade payables at the end of the year?","A":"bad debt written off","B":"discount allowed","C":"returns inwards","D":"returns outwards","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"The issued share capital of CD Limited consists of ordinary shares. Retained earnings were $86 000 on 1 September 2016 and $88 500 on 31 August 2017. The company made a profit during the year of $26 000 and made a transfer to general reserve of $5000. What was the total ordinary share dividend paid during the year?","A":"$18 500","B":"$23 500","C":"$28 500","D":"$33 500","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which document shows employees the details of deductions made from their wages?","A":"clock card","B":"payslip","C":"time sheet","D":"wages sheet","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is not included when calculating the quick ratio (acid test ratio)?","A":"bank overdraft","B":"inventory","C":"short-term bank loan","D":"trade receivables","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Manvinder started a business and paid a cheque for $1000 into a business bank account. He recorded this in the books of the business by debiting the bank account and crediting the capital account. Which accounting principles did he apply?","A":"accounting entity and dual aspect","B":"accounting entity and going concern","C":"going concern and matching /accruals","D":"matching / accruals and dual aspect","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(12)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What would be the most useful way of monitoring the progress of a retail business?","A":"comparing the financial statements of one year with those of previous years","B":"comparing the financial statements with those of a business in another country","C":"comparing the financial statements with those of a business of a different size","D":"comparing the financial statements with those of a manufacturing business","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which statement about a computerised accounting system is correct?","A":"Anyone with a computer can gain access to the accounting records.","B":"Data input can only be used for one specific purpose.","C":"Data output can only be understood by computer programmers.","D":"Operator error may result in inaccurate information.","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What increases owner’s capital?","A":"bank loan extended from five to ten years","B":"purchase of inventory on credit","C":"purchase of machinery by cheque","D":"transfer of vehicle to business from private use","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which account always has a credit balance?","A":"capital account","B":"cash account","C":"drawings account","D":"premises account","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Kamal purchases and sells goods on credit. Where does he maintain the accounts of his credit suppliers?","A":"purchases journal","B":"purchases ledger","C":"sales journal","D":"sales ledger","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which transaction of a manufacturer would be entered in the general journal?","A":"payment of wages by cash","B":"purchase of raw materials on credit","C":"sales of finished goods on credit","D":"writing off a bad debt","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"10 The totals of a trial balance agreed. What does this mean?","A":"All the arithmetic in the ledger is correct.","B":"All transactions have been entered in the correct ledger accounts.","C":"All transactions have been entered on the correct sides of the ledger.","D":"Total debit balances equal total credit balances in the ledger","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Ann’s financial year ends on 31 August. The annual rates on her shop are $3000. On 1 September 2016 rates prepaid amounted to $750. Rates paid during the year ended 31 August 2017 amounted to $2750. What was the balance brought down on the rates account on 1 September 2017?","A":"$250 credit","B":"$250 debit","C":"$500 credit","D":"$500 debit","Answer":"D","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A trader incorrectly posted sales returns of $100 to the credit of purchases returns account. What was the effect on the gross profit?","A":"overstated $100","B":"overstated $200","C":"understated $100","D":"understated $200","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which business is not a service business?","A":"accountant’s practice","B":"computer repair shop","C":"flower shop","D":"hairdressing salon","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What is a disadvantage of forming a partnership?","A":"additional skills are available","B":"profits are shared","C":"responsibilities are shared","D":"risks are shared","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"A golf club has 230 members. The annual subscription is $100. At the beginning of the year subscriptions prepaid amounted to $1000 and at the end of the year subscriptions in arrears amounted to $1500. How much did the club receive for subscriptions during the year?","A":"$20500","B":"$22500","C":"$23500","D":"$25500","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"What would not appear in the income and expenditure account of a sports club?","A":"cost of sports equipment","B":"depreciation of sports equipment","C":"insurance of sports equipment","D":"repairs to sports equipment","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Karim did not keep proper accounting records, but was able to provide the following information. capital at 1 January 58000, drawings during the year 8500, capital introduced in the year 15000, capital at 31 December 82500. What was the profit for the year?","A":"$16000","B":"$18000","C":"$33000","D":"$48000","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Sumit does not maintain a full set of accounting records. What does Sumit not need to calculate his credit sales?","A":"customer’s dishonoured cheque","B":"discounts allowed","C":"discounts received","D":"returns inwards","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Which is shown as loan capital in the statement of financial position of a limited company?","A":"bank overdraft","B":"debentures","C":"ordinary shares","D":"preference shares","Answer":"B","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"Stephan’s major competitor has invested in a new machine for making goods more cheaply. Stephan knows this will affect his sales but did not record this in his accounting records. Which accounting principle is Stephan applying?","A":"going concern","B":"materiality","C":"money measurement","D":"prudence","Answer":"C","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"},{"Question":"At the end of the financial year Omar’s inventory was 100 units of which 10 units were damaged and could not be sold. The selling price per unit is $5 and the cost price per unit is $3.50. Which value should Omar place on his inventory?","A":"$315","B":"$350","C":"$450","D":"$500","Answer":"A","Category":"","Guess":"","Year":"NOV2017(11)","Qualification":"Cambridge-IGCSE","Subject":"Accounting"}]